Where am I...?
這裡是哪裡?
Huh?
什麼?
Somebody...
有沒有人在?
Somebody, help me! Somebody!
有人在嗎?救救我!來人啊!
Ah, you're awake already, Big Sister.
哎呀,姊姊,妳已經醒來啦?
How are you feeling?
覺得怎麼樣啊?
Did you have a good dream?
有沒有做個好夢?
MY HAPPY MARRIAGE
我的幸福婚約
EPISODE 6 DETERMINATION AND THUNDER
第 6 集 劇名:決心與雷鳴
We need to go faster!
請加快速度!
Being impatient like that won't make things better.
就算你著急成那樣情況也不會改變
You should calm down a little.
冷靜一點
You're awfully calm for someone whose fiancée was kidnapped.
你的未婚妻現在都不知道 遭受到什麼樣的對待了
We have no idea what she's going through.
你還真是冷靜呢
Are you sure of her whereabouts?
你確定她現在真的在那裡?
Yes. I'm certain Miyo is...
是的,美世...
at the Saimori house.
應該就在齋森家
Since you took so long to come to, I thought your heart finally stopped.
姊姊一直沒醒來 害我以為妳的心臟停止了呢
W-Why are you doing this to me?
妳是為了什麼才做出這種事?
You are very irritating.
妳真是討人厭
You should have stayed a servant or died in a ditch somewhere.
妳就該乖乖當個僕人或是死在路邊
You should know your place!
真是不知分寸!
I order you to reject Mr. Kudo's marriage proposal right now.
妳現在就去拒絕久堂先生的婚約
Listen carefully.
聽好了
You must tell him directly that you reject his offer.
妳得親口對久堂先生說 要拒絕這樁婚約
After all, being a wife to Mr. Kudo is too much of a burden for you, I think.
因為我認為對姊姊來說 當久堂先生的妻子負擔太大了
That pretty kimono you're wearing, for example...
竟然還穿著那麼漂亮的和服
Don't you think it's out of step with your position?
不覺得不符合自己的身分嗎?
Say, won't you promise us that you'll reject his marriage proposal?
我問妳,能不能答應我 會拒絕這婚事?
Otherwise, I will have to remake this precious kimono of yours...
不然這件妳最寶貝的和服...
to match your lowly position, Big Sister.
就得重新製成符合妳身分的樣子囉
Since you got him to buy you such an expensive kimono,
妳都能要求他買這麼昂貴的和服了
it should be easy for you to scrap the marriage proposal.
那取消婚事應該也能 輕而易舉地做到吧
Once I get engaged to Mr. Kudo,
我和久堂先生訂婚後
I'll give Koji back to you.
就會將幸次先生還給妳
Well, Big Sister?
來吧,姊姊
What are you going to say to Mr. Kudo?
說說看妳要對久堂先生說什麼?
No...
不...
No?
“不”?
Stop it...
不要這樣...
- No! - That's incorrect.
-不要! -不對吧
- Don't! - Those are not the words I want to hear.
-我想聽到的不是那種話
Let me hear from your mouth, Big Sister.
讓我聽妳親口說吧,姊姊
Say that you'll reject
快說妳會
his marriage offer.
拒絕這樁婚事
Why?
為什麼?
Why is this happening?
為什麼會發生這種事?
It would be easy for me to give up now.
現在放棄一定很簡單
But this...
不過唯有這件事...
this is the one thing I don't want to give away to anyone.
只有未婚妻的身分 我不想讓給任何人
What's the matter? Did you lose your voice?
怎麼了?發不出聲音嗎?
You are so useless, Big Sister.
姊姊,妳真的很沒用呢
I can't...
我...
I can't give in...
我不要
to a demand like that.
我不能聽從...
I won't do it.
妳的那種要求!
Don't defy us!
少在那邊狂妄了!
You little...
妳這個...
Mother?
母親大人
Leave it to me.
就交給我吧
Like I thought, the floor suits you better, Big Sister.
姊姊還是適合躺在地板上
Hey. You're a failure, aren't you?
我問妳喔,姊姊是個廢物對吧?
Unlike me, you have neither Spirit-Sight nor any redeeming qualities.
和我不一樣,沒有見鬼之才 而且還一無是處
An embarrassment to the family like you can't possibly be Mr. Kudo's wife.
姊姊是我們家的恥辱 怎麼可能當久堂先生的妻子
It was a mistake from the start.
打從一開始就是個錯誤
- Hey! Open the gate! -Don't you think this'll be good for you?
-喂!快開門! -不覺得這樣很好嗎?
You'll have this Saimori house and Koji as your own.
這個齋森家和幸次先生都將會是妳的
Isn't that what you've wanted all along, Big Sister?
姊姊不是一直都很想要這些嗎?
I...
我...
I am the one...
我才是...
I'm the fiancée...
老爺的...
I'm the fiancée of Kiyoka Kudo.
久堂清霞的未婚妻
I'll never give that up.
我絕對不會讓步
What the...
妳說什麼?
Enough is enough!
給我適可而止!
You owe me for raising you till now.
虧我把妳養到這麼大
But you bite the hand that fed you as soon as you left to marry, huh?
嫁人後就忘了養育之恩 而且還恩將仇報
My, such a nasty child!
真是個討人厭的孩子!
I'm not gonna let someone like you ruin my life!
我不會讓妳這種人 打亂我人生的步調!
If it was me from the past, I would have apologized...
如果是以前的我,一定會道歉
just to let the storm pass... That's how I lived.
希望風暴趕快平息 我一直都是那樣活過來的
It was easier that way.
畢竟那樣比較輕鬆
But I don't want to give up.
不過我不想要放棄
I'm not the person I used to be who couldn't do anything.
我已經不是過去那個 什麼都做不到的自己了
I want to go back...
我要回到...
to where my husband-to-be is.
老爺身邊!
Hey, stand back a little.
喂,你稍微後退
Whoa.
什麼?
What a poor loser you are!
妳還真纏人!
What was that?!
怎麼回事?
What the...
竟然...
I can't believe it.
竟然做出這種事
Let's go.
走吧
Huh? Uh, right!
什麼?啊,好!
What's going on?!
發生什麼事了?
Mr. Kudo! Stop!
久堂先生!請等一下!
Explain this to me!
到底發生了什麼事?
Where is Miyo, Mr. Saimori?
美世在哪裡?齋森先生
Miyo?
美世?
If this is about Miyo, she won't be returning to the Kudo house any longer.
要找美世的話,她不會再回久堂家了
Father! How could you...?
爸,你這個人真的是...
Kiyoka Kudo.
久堂清霞
I didn't expect you here so quickly.
沒想到你這麼快就來了
Where is my fiancée?
我的未婚妻在哪裡?
Miyo won't see you anymore.
美世說她不想再見你
She said she's not going back.
也不會回去
I'll verify her will by asking her myself.
她本人的意願 我要親口聽到才會相信
If you can't answer me, get out of my way.
不想回答的話就給我讓開
I refuse.
我拒絕
If you're forcing your way in,
如果你硬要通過
we won't just silently sit back and watch.
我們也不會坐視不管
Then, I will use force to enter.
那麼我會強行通過
W-Wait!
等一下!
What in the world is going on, Tatsuishi?
到底是怎麼回事?辰石
Ask your daughter later.
之後再去問你的女兒吧
The main gate was blown to pieces.
正門已經被燒得粉碎了
If you let him in, the whole house might get destroyed.
如果放任他繼續闖入 這座宅邸也可能會被破壞
If that bothers you, then you must lend a hand.
不想演變成那樣的話你也要幫忙
- Hah!
-看招!
He's the head of the Kudo family all right.
真不愧是久堂家的當家
They're just wasting time.
這只是在白費力氣
Is he a genuine monster...?
難道他是真正的怪物?
You're in the way.
別擋路
Move.
讓開
They're no match for him.
他們根本不是對手
Their power is like babies in comparison.
他們的實力差距 簡直就像大人對上嬰兒
So this demonstrates...
這就是...
the potential of the most powerful supernatural ability of today...
當代最強異能者的實力嗎?
What was that sound?
剛剛那是什麼聲音?
I'm tired of your behavior!
真是讓人看不下去!
Hurry up and say it!
快說出來!
Say that you'll reject the Kudo family's offer!
說妳會拒絕久堂家的婚約!
No, I won't.
我不要
You brat!
妳這個傢伙!
I'm telling you to remember your place!
我是叫妳搞清楚自己是什麼身分!
I'll never surrender to you.
為了相信我的老爺
For my husband-to-be who believes in me, I'll stand my ground!
我說什麼都不會讓步!
Miyo...
美世...
A storehouse?
庫房?
Yes.
是的
There is an old storehouse that's rarely used now.
有個現在幾乎不使用的老舊庫房
Perhaps Miyo was taken there.
美世說不定就在那裡
Show me the way to it.
帶我去吧
Yes.
好
Don't let him go there!
我不會讓你過去的!
Father!
爸!
Using fire in a place like this?
你究竟是有多愚蠢
How could you be so foolish?
才會在這種地方使用火焰?
This is dreadful...
竟然做出這種事
I won't let you take Miyo!
我說什麼都不會把美世交給你!
That's enough.
到此為止了
I just knocked him unconscious.
我只是讓他昏迷而已
Let's hurry.
動作快
Why is this happening?
事情為什麼會變成這樣?
Say it already! Say that you won't marry him!
妳給我快說!說妳會拒絕婚約!
Now!
快給我說!
In the past, I was just waiting for my time to die.
以前的我一直在等待死期的到來
Every single day brought more suffering and sadness.
每天都過得痛苦又難過
I was tired of living with my emotions shut off.
即使在扼殺內心情感的情況下 活著也疲憊不已
There wasn't any place where I belonged. That's what I always thought.
我曾以為這世界上沒有我的容身之處
But...
但是...
I was wrong.
我發現自己錯了
I'm the one who wants you to be here.
我希望妳能留在這裡
This was the place where I belonged.
我有了容身之處
Next to him.
就在那個人的身邊
Say it! Hurry up!
說啊!快點給我聽話!
I won't... I'll never say it...
我絕對不會說
Say it!
妳給我說!
I will be...
我一定要...
by his side...
回到老爺身邊
Mr. Kudo?
久堂先生?
Miyo!
美世!
Oh...
啊
He really came for me.
他真的來救我了
Sir...
老爺
I... never gave up, sir.
我沒有放棄喔
Miyo.
美世
Sir...
老爺
You'll be okay now.
已經沒事了
You came all the way here for someone like me.
謝謝你為了我這種人
Thank you... very much.
特地趕到這裡
What's with all this noise?
從剛剛開始就傳來的 到底是什麼聲音?
No... This can't be.
怎麼會這樣?不...
No!
不要啊!
What were you doing to her until now?
妳們做了什麼才把她折磨成這樣?
She had no way to resist. What were you trying to achieve
妳們把一個無法抵抗的人 弄得傷痕累累
by hurting her this much?
是為了什麼?
I didn't do anything wrong.
那不是我的錯
All I wanted to do was to correct a mistake, that's it.
我當時就只是想改正錯誤而已
A mistake?
“錯誤”?
Big Sister doesn't have Spirit-Sight, her appearance is scrawny,
姊姊沒有見鬼之才,外表又寒酸
and she was even incompetent as a servant.
連當僕人都派不上用場
It must be a mistake for a person like that to be accepted into your family.
久堂家才不會接納那種人 一定是出了什麼差錯吧
My father and mother both say that I'm the best one.
父親大人和母親大人 也都說我才是最棒的
They say I'm nothing like Big Sister.
和姊姊大不相同
I'm superior in every way to--
在所有事情上我都比她...
Shut up.
閉嘴
I don't want to hear any more nonsense from you.
我不想再聽妳繼續胡說八道了
Why? Why don't you understand?
為什麼?為何你就是不懂呢?
It's not fair!
太過分了!
I've heard enough of your stupid bragging.
我已經對妳無聊的自吹自擂 感到厭煩了
There's not a chance in hell I would choose an arrogant woman like you.
就算天地反轉我也不可能 選擇妳這種傲慢的女人
Get out of the way.
讓開
How...
為什麼...
How can this happen?
為什麼會變成這樣?
Kaya, we should evacuate too.
香耶,我們也去避難吧
I wasn't wrong.
我沒有錯
Let go! Just leave me alone!
放開我!讓我一個人待著!
Be quiet!
給我安靜!
What are you doing?
幹嘛啊?
Big Sister is the one you love, right?
幸次先生不是喜歡姊姊嗎?
You don't care about me. Just flee on your own!
別管我了,你自己趕快逃不就好了?
Yeah, you're right. The one I care for is Miyo!
沒錯,正如妳所說的 我最重視的是美世!
But Miyo would lament your death if you die, even if it's you.
不過就算是妳這樣的人 妳死了美世也會傷心
It would leave another painful scar on her.
讓她的內心又增添新的傷痕
And it would be because of you... no, because of us.
會是因為妳...不,是因為我們的過錯
That's why I'm not leaving here without you.
所以我絕對不會丟下妳不管
My, you've grown, Miyo.
妳長大了呢,美世
Mother!
母親大人!
I'm sorry you had to go through so much hardship because of me.
讓妳在各方面都受苦了,對不起
You have to believe in yourself.
妳要相信自己喔
Believe in the power you have inside you.
堅信自己內在的那股力量
The power...
我的...
inside me?
力量?
Atrocious.
真是可惡
Obnoxious.
讓人可恨
Such an annoyance.
實在是太煩人了
That useless Tatsuishi.
辰石那個沒用的傢伙
At this rate, the Usuba blood will be possessed by the Kudo family.
再這樣下去 久堂家將擁有薄刃家的血脈
Your Majesty.
陛下
I would like to ask for your permission.
針對之前的事 差不多想請求您的許可
Please give us the opportunity to fulfill our long-cherished wish.
還請您請給我們機會 實現長久以來的夙願
So that the thing is placed where it belongs...
讓其回歸所屬之地
The situation will change soon.
再過不久情況就會有所變動
I authorize your action.
我允許你行動
However, do not get the timing wrong.
但是千萬別錯失時機
Yes, Your Majesty.
遵命
Then as discussed,
那就照安排
we will commence the plan.
我們將展開行動
Do not fail
你可別失敗
to crush that supernatural ability.
一定要擊潰那個異能
Sir...
老爺...
Miyo!
美世!
Sir!
老爺!
Yes, it's me.
對,是我
Don't push yourself. Stay in bed.
妳別勉強,躺著吧
Um...
那個...
But...
不過...
Are you really all right?
妳真的沒事嗎?
Yes. Uh, sir...
我沒事,那個,老爺
This all happened because I was not careful enough...
這次都怪我自己不注意,所以...
It wasn't your fault.
這不是妳的錯
Not at all. None of it was.
妳一點錯都沒有
You're not to blame.
完全沒有錯
Thank you very much,
真的很感謝你
sir.
老爺
Ms. Miyo!
美世小姐!
Ms. Yurie.
由里江小姐
Ms. Miyo! I'm so relieved!
美世小姐!太好了!
I'm so glad you've awakened!
您醒來真是太好了!
Ms. Yurie, please raise your head.
由里江小姐,請妳抬起頭來吧
I was so worried about your condition.
我一直都很擔心
If something happened to you, I'd...
想說美世小姐要是 出了什麼事該如何是好
We're so happy you're safe, Miyo.
妳平安無事真是太好了,美世
Yes.
是
Subtitle translation by: Ikuko Ohno
字幕翻譯:洪禎韓